INTEGRATION ARCHITECT

Career Overview

12+ years of IT Services industry experience in EAI and Client/Server application design, which includes over 10 years of integration experience using webMethods, 6 years of experience using MuleSoft and 1 year experience using SAP Cloud Platform Integration, Process Orchestration and Dell Boomi

Qualifications

- MuleSoft Certified Integration Architect, MuleSoft Certified Platform Architect & MuleSoft Certified Developer
- Expert in EAI and B2B integration architecture, design and development
- Developed integration solutions using various AWS and Azure services
- Experience with evaluation of MuleSoft, Dell Boomi, Informatica Cloud, SAP CPI, Logic Apps and Apigee
- Expert in various integration technologies like SOAP, REST, HTTP, FTP, XML, JSON, AS2 etc
- Knowledgeable in Integration Architectural guidelines and designing Integration patterns
- Expert in Full API Lifecycle Management and cloud based integrations using microservices
- Experience in implementing numerous projects using MuleSoft, webMethods and SAP Process Orchestration technologies for multiple clients

Work Experience

02/2020 to Current

Integration Architect Zoominfo il/4 San Mateo, CA

- Provided Integration strategy and helped Nexeo Plastics spin-off as a private company
- Worked with MuleSoft and SAP to demo and procure new Integration platforms(iPaas)
- Stood up a new Integration platform on AWS to refactor and migrate over 350 on-prem interfaces from legacy company
- $\bullet \ \ \ Designed \ and \ developed \ around \ 100 \ interfaces \ using \ Mulesoff, \ webMethods \ and \ SAP \ CPI \ in a 4 \ month \ time \ period \ to \ accommodate \ transition \ service \ agreement \ \hat{A} \ \hat{A}$
- Designed user interfaces in SAP Fiori/UI5 to simplify employee onboarding process with SuccessFactors
- Developed APIs for various applications such as SAP, Salesforce, SuccessFactors, Connectwise etc and surfaced them on a new API portal for the company
- Worked with over 50 B2B/EDI partners to setup integrations from our cloud landscape

03/2017 to 02/2020

Integration Architect Epiroc il/4 Nevada, MO

- Designed several integrations for Murphy Oil using MuleSoft's Anypoint platform
- Helped expose APIs from various systems and promote C4E culture within the company
- Worked with several Murphy Oil Business lines and vendors to improve integration and data exposure capabilities for critical systems like SAP, SuccessFactors, ADP Vantage etc.
- Helped transition integrations from Dell Boomi and SAP PO to MuleSoftÂ
- Worked with MuleSoft Services and customer success teams to develop API-led network for Murphy Oil
- Implemented a low-cost global FTP solution using Thru OptiPaas platform
- Worked on Azure log analytics, Elastic Stack and AWS Quicksight to report on KPIs for MuleSoft using Anypoint platform APIs
- Helped setup CI/CD using Azure devops with git
- Provided analysis on comparison of various Integration platforms such as MuleSoft, SAP CPI and Logic Apps to provide guidance for IT leadership
- Designed various UI applications on Outsystems platform that integrate with MuleSoft APIs

01/2012 to 02/2017

Integration Architect Epiroc il/4 Pa, PA

- Worked on several important projects involving webMethods, MuleSoft, SAP Process Orchestration and Dell Boomi
- Responsible for maintaining and updating Integration Strategy based on current and future Integration needs across all platforms
- Developed Integration Reference Architecture with patterns and governance model including exception processes to deviate from standard patterns
- Responsible for architecture, design and development of interfaces with over 500 trading partners and internal applications
- Involved in MuleSoft Introduction Project to implement MuleSoft as a strategic service to integrate cloud and on-premise applications
- Implemented several cloud based integration projects including Salesforce, Ariba and GEP
- Worked directly with various vendors to implement new functionalities and enhance integration platforms

02/2011 to 12/2011

Senior WebMethods Consultant Gavilon LLC i1/4 City, STATE

- The information sent from multiple commodity trading systems is created in Oracle R12 EBS using the webMethods Oracle APPS adapter.
- We used the Oracle Public API's to create Supplier, Customer and Bank Account Information in accordance with Trading Community Architecture.
- The data retrieved is mapped to the records in the Oracle Apps Server and the API to create the Supplier, Customer or Bank Account is invoked.

The Oracle Public API's are wrapped in custom PL/SQL packages. The custom stored procedures are invoked by defining an Oracle to IS
transaction in webMethods Oracle APPS adapter administration page. These transactions are used to create the webMethods Adapter
services.

03/2010 to 01/2011

WebMethods Consultant Life Technologies i1/4 City, STATE

- The project involved XML integration between Life technologies and Kenexa Recruiter Brass Ring(KRB) for hiring
- Life technologies send the job description, department, location, employee data(managers and recruiters) to Kenexa. The data comes from SAP to webMethods through RFC.
- The data is transformed into Kenexa XML tags and sent by HTTPS.
- Kenexa evaluates these candidate resumes with job description, requirements and selects suitable candidate profile which is later sent to Life technologies.

08/2009 to 02/2010

Webmethods Consultant Dish Network i1/4 City, STATE

- Worked on several EDI integrations between Trading partners and internal systems.
- Used EDI X12 and EDIFACT standards

06/2008 to 06/2009

Java & WebMethods Consultant Spartan Stores i1/4 City, STATE

Worked on integrating existing partners and new partners, data synchronization between legacy DB2 systems and Oracle applications.

Education and Training

2006

Bachelor of Science: Electronics & Instrumentation Vellore Institute of Technology India

2008

Master of Science : Electronics & Computers University of Houston il 4 City , State , United States